<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,2016-56-20:/201656201463784976</id>
    <title>brittcrawford.com</title>
    <updated>2016-05-20T22:56:16Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>BrittCrawford</name>
        <email>britt@illtemper.org</email>
        <uri>http://brittcrawford.com/</uri>
        <uri>http://brittcrawford.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://brittcrawford.com/"/>
    <subtitle>ThepersonalsiteofBrittCrawford</subtitle>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2016, BrittCrawford</rights>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <contributor>
        <name>BrittCrawford</name>
        <email>britt@illtemper.org</email>
    </contributor>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading May 15th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1463295600000:/reading/2016-05-15/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-05-15/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-05-15T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-15" class="date-read">Sunday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.interfluidity.com/v2/6451.html" class="title" target="_blank">interfluidity » Difference</a><summary class="description">Matt Yglesias, with characteristic perceptiveness, points out (ht DeLong ) that There are significant and salient tension between the economic and…</summary><section class="my-notes">I think I&#x27;m probably a Universalist Liberal just below the x-axis.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://ngnghm.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/chapter-1-the-way-houyhnhnms-compute/" class="title" target="_blank">Chapter 1: The Way Houyhnhnms Compute</a><summary class="description">Dear fellow programmer, I used to think humans wrote software the way they did because they knew what they were doing. Then I realized that they didn’t really…</summary><section class="my-notes">I&#x27;m not wild about using design fiction to convey a point of view about computing or user interface (unless you&#x27;re _why). It often comes off as condescending. This piece certainly does, but the point it makes is a good one.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/muscles-genes-cheats-2012-olympics-london/" class="title" target="_blank">Unnatural Selection: Muscles, Genes and Genetic Cheats</a><summary class="description">Credit: Courtesy of PeskyMonkey, via iStockphoto.com Take a close look at the athletes competing in this year&#x27;s Summer Olympic Games in London —their…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-16" class="date-read">Monday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.interfluidity.com/v2/5031.html" class="title" target="_blank">interfluidity » “Incentives to produce” are incentives to rig the game</a><summary class="description">That’s obvious, right? But let’s belabor the point. All too often in discussions about the vast dispersion of circumstance we call “inequality”, people concede…</summary><section class="my-notes">Yes, always. Demand is the incentive to produce. With the exception of inflating a non-existent market, see &quot;On the Road to Recap&quot; or the solar industry, supply side incentives are rents to be captured.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-17" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://abovethecrowd.com/2016/04/21/on-the-road-to-recap/" class="title" target="_blank">On the Road to Recap: | Above the Crowd</a><summary class="description">April 21, 2016: Why the Unicorn Financing Market Just Became Dangerous…For All Involved In February of last year, Fortune magazine writers Erin Griffith and Dan…</summary><section class="my-notes">Clear explanation of &quot;the Steroid Era&quot; of startups. How raising massive amounts of capital could be used as the key competitive tool, especially in two sided marketplaces, and how hard it is to do well. Uber and AirBnB are the best examples of using capital to inflate a marketplace. Buy supply. Then buy demand. Really you buy both simultanesouly but supply needs to lead deamnd slightly. Then buy speed to market and scale. If you don&#x27;t buy all four you will fail. In an environment where massive amounts of capital can be raised cheaply, being able to raise money and deploy it in this way is the key skill for success.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-18" class="date-read">Wednesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://narrative.ly/lessons-from-a-local-food-scam-artist/" class="title" target="_blank">Lessons From a ‘Local Food’ Scam Artist</a><summary class="description">I met my first New York foodie over twenty years ago, when I was seventeen, hawking “local bananas” at a roadside produce stand in rural New Jersey. It was my…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/how-i-acted-like-a-pundit-and-screwed-up-on-donald-trump/" class="title" target="_blank">How I Acted Like A Pundit And Screwed Up On Donald Trump</a><summary class="description">Since Donald Trump effectively wrapped up the Republican nomination this month, I’ve seen a lot of critical self-assessments from empirically minded journalists…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-19" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://taylorpearson.me/idealday/" class="title" target="_blank">How to Plan Your Ideal Day</a><summary class="description">“How we spend our days is, of course, how we spend our lives. What we do with this hour and with that one, is what we are doing.” – Annie Dillard How do we do…</summary><section class="my-notes">When I got to the section where he talks about eating the same thing everyday for the last two years I knew this advice wasn&#x27;t for me. &quot;Systems over goals&quot; and setting up habits that encourage the kind of work you want to produce are great ideas, but this approach will not work for me. People that can industrialize their livesin this way are a mystery to me. I&#x27;ve tried creating a routine like this and maintaining consistency consumes all of my energy and drains any energy I might use for creative work. I try and create an environment  that nudges me in the right direction, but where I can still be spontaneous and experience a lot of novelty and variety. I am not good at it. This temperament probably excludes from ever being a great athlete or polymath. </section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-20" class="date-read">Friday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160519144533.htm" class="title" target="_blank">Scientists create &#x27;rewritable magnetic charge ice&#x27;</a><summary class="description">A depiction of the global order of magnetic charge ice. Orange-red areas represent the positive charges; blue areas represent negative charges. A team of…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.the-american-interest.com/2016/02/25/heideggers-ghosts/" class="title" target="_blank">Heidegger’s Ghosts</a><summary class="description">Heidegger has powerful adherents in societies as different as Russia and Iran. If liberal democracies are to reckon with his followers, they must wrestle with…</summary></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading May 8th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1462690800000:/reading/2016-05-08/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-05-08/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-05-08T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-10" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://medium.com/@arnaudrinquin/build-modular-application-with-npm-local-modules-dfc5ff047bcc" class="title" target="_blank">Build modular application with npm local modules</a><summary class="description">Rationale Most large javascript application built using npm modules have the same problem: tons of javascript files stored in deeply nested folders. You will…</summary><section class="my-notes">I never knew node had a local mode. Neat.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://wholehealthsource.blogspot.com/2016/05/why-some-dogs-and-humans-are-born-hungry.html" class="title" target="_blank">Whole Health Source: Why some dogs (and humans) are born hungry</a><summary class="description">The brain is the central regulator of appetite and body fatness, and genetic variation that affects body fatness tends to act in the brain. One important site…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-11" class="date-read">Wednesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.messynessychic.com/2014/12/11/the-rotting-underwater-ballroom-of-a-victorian-bernie-madoff/" class="title" target="_blank">The Rotting Underwater Ballroom of a Victorian Bernie Madoff</a><summary class="description">Beneath the lake of a once lavish Victorian estate built by a flamboyant mining tycoon, a secret awaits… (c) Forgotten Heritage At murkey water’s edge, a stone…</summary><section class="my-notes">Brilliant and beautiful, the Victorians really had to create a culture of otherworldly fantasy to hide from themselves the mountain of skulls that their society was built on.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2013/03/behold-the-hatred-resentment-and-mockery-aimed-at-anti-iraq-war-protesters/274230/" class="title" target="_blank">Behold the Hatred, Resentment, and Mockery Aimed at Anti-Iraq War Protesters</a><summary class="description">Reflecting on the apologetic Iraq War retrospectives many writers have published in recent days, Freddie deBoer observes that &quot;one of the most obvious…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://fredrikdeboer.com/2016/05/03/ernest-hemingway-joins-the-content-industry/" class="title" target="_blank">Ernest Hemingway Joins the #Content Industry</a><summary class="description">With thanks to JB Miller and Papa. There were twelve of us, in the elevator, myself and two other interviewees and all of the regular readers of Fusion. I was…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-12" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/10/opinion/sunday/how-not-to-explain-success.html" class="title" target="_blank">How Not to Explain Success</a><summary class="description">Oscar Bolton Green DO you remember the controversy two years ago, when the Yale law professors Amy Chua (author of “Battle Hymn of the Tiger Mother”) and Jed…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-14" class="date-read">Saturday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://kneelingbus.wordpress.com/2016/04/29/an-environment-smarter-than-you-are/" class="title" target="_blank">An Environment Smarter than You Are</a><summary class="description">Posted: April 29, 2016 | Author: | Filed under: Uncategorized | “Basic” is the best insult to emerge in the last few years, a slicing, leveling adjective…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://jpkoning.blogspot.com/2016/05/what-makes-medieval-money-different.html" class="title" target="_blank">Moneyness: What makes medieval money different from modern money?</a><summary class="description">What&#x27;s the main difference between our modern monetary system and the system they had in the medieval ages? Most of you will probably answer something along the…</summary><section class="my-notes">I didn&#x27;t realize that Medeival money was valued by decree. That&#x27;s real fiat currency.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://stratechery.com/2016/antitrust-and-aggregation/" class="title" target="_blank">Antitrust and Aggregation - Stratechery by Ben Thompson</a><summary class="description">Fifteen years on, perhaps the most pertinent takeaway from Microsoft’s antitrust battles with both the United States and Europe is how little it mattered. From…</summary></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading May 1st, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1462086000000:/reading/2016-05-01/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-05-01/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-05-01T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-05-03" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://opencontent.org/blog/archives/4529" class="title" target="_blank">OER: Some Questions and Answers</a><summary class="description">Earlier this week I read an op-ed – sponsored by Pearson – titled “If OER is the answer, what is the question?” The article poses three questions and answers…</summary><section class="my-notes">Pearson seems to re-arguing Wikipedia vs. Britannica. I think ultimately the results will be similar.</section></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading April 24th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1461481200000:/reading/2016-04-24/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-04-24/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-04-24T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-25" class="date-read">Monday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://jpospisil.com/2014/06/16/the-definitive-guide-to-arel-the-sql-manager-for-ruby.html" class="title" target="_blank">The definitive guide to Arel, the SQL manager for Ruby - Jiri Pospisil&#x27;s blog</a><summary class="description">Written by Jiří Pospíšil, a full stack developer currently working primarily with Ruby on Rails and Ember.js.You can get in touch with me at…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-26" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://gizmodo.com/wikipedia-is-basically-a-corporate-bureaucracy-accordi-1746955234" class="title" target="_blank">Wikipedia Is Basically a Corporate Bureaucracy, According to a New Study</a><summary class="description">Image: Wikipedia Wikipedia is a voluntary organization dedicated to the noble goal of decentralized knowledge creation. But as the community has evolved over…</summary><section class="my-notes">Norms are really really hard to change and mostly don&#x27;t.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://medium.com/fluxx-studio-notes/the-first-rule-of-pricing-is-you-do-not-talk-about-pricing-1875caa39b89" class="title" target="_blank">The first rule of pricing is: you do not talk about pricing — Fluxx Studio Notes</a><summary class="description">I’ve been slightly obsessed about pricing since 2010. Before joining Fluxx , I was part of the team that changed the price of The Times digital edition from…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://priceonomics.com/why-thieves-steal-soap/" class="title" target="_blank">Why Thieves Steal Soap</a><summary class="description">Why Thieves Steal Soap Apr 14, 2016 · 89,714 views This article was written by Alex Mayyasi , a Priceonomics staff writer If you want to buy soap at the…</summary><section class="my-notes">Liquidity über alles.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-27" class="date-read">Wednesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.nakedcapitalism.com/2016/04/uber-spends-100-million-to-save-its-business-model-but-it-may-have-just-doomed-it.html" class="title" target="_blank">Uber Spends $100 Million to Save its Business Model, But It May Have Just Doomed It | naked capitalism</a><summary class="description">By David Dayen, author of Chain of Title: How Three Ordinary Americans Uncovered Wall Street’s Great Foreclosure Fraud , releasing May 17. I’ve written before…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://news.greylock.com/why-uber-won-5598a2a66561#.vx4me4u8n" class="title" target="_blank">Why Uber Won — Greylock Perspectives</a><summary class="description">The Startup Steroid Era and the Use of Capital as a Performance Enhancing Drug</summary><section class="my-notes">Uber was the best at using cheap capital to accelerate growth simultanesouly buying speed to market and scale on both sides of it&#x27;s marketplace. This article dubs 2010-2015 &quot;The Steroid Era&quot; of startups when the ability to raise money and wield capital as a weapon was the key skill necessary to succeed.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-28" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2016/04/a-protest-against-the-protesters-at-uc-davis/479256/" class="title" target="_blank">How &#x27;Safe Spaces&#x27; Are Being Turned Against Student Activists</a><summary class="description">At UC Davis, where student activists still hope to oust Chancellor Linda Katehi, critics of their activism are using concepts like “safe space” and “hostile…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://news.utexas.edu/2016/04/25/risks-of-harm-from-spanking-confirmed-by-researchers?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=utnewsshares" class="title" target="_blank">Risks of Harm from Spanking Confirmed by Analysis of Five Decades of Research</a><summary class="description">AUSTIN, Texas ­ — The more children are spanked, the more likely they are to defy their parents and to experience increased anti-social behavior, aggression,…</summary><section class="my-notes">Opression builds resentment and creates the environment that is it&#x27;s own undoing. Who knew?</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.bulletproofexec.com/mycotoxins-in-america/" class="title" target="_blank">Our Moldy World Part 1: Mycotoxins</a><summary class="description">Share: Some new research has come to light that provides an explanation for why the problem of mycotoxins (mold toxins) in our food supply is becoming worse.…</summary><section class="my-notes">This seems well researched, but it could be well researched and wrong. Who knows? I just discovered I&#x27;ve been living in a very moldy house and am a bit freaked out. The article on risk perception is very appropriate here.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://undark.org/article/know-this-first-risk-perception-is-always-irrational/" class="title" target="_blank">Know This First: Risk Perception is Always Irrational.</a><summary class="description">IN 2011, the city leaders of Calgary, Alberta, bowed to public pressure and ended fluoridation of the local drinking water, despite clear evidence that the…</summary><section class="my-notes">Risk perception is a matter of feelings not rationality. Try to communicate about risk with the language of rationality will fail. Risk communication must begin by engaging with fear and the feelings of the person you are trying to persuade. This highlights the problemn with the deficit theory. &quot;These people are just uneducated. If they knew more they wouldn&#x27;t think this way.&quot; is completely wrong.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://muller.lbl.gov/pages/Muller-theorems.htm" class="title" target="_blank">Muller&#x27;s theorems</a><summary class="description">1. Theorem: if ithappens, it must be possible. 2. Theorem: We never takecredit for our best skills for they come without effort. 3. Corollary…</summary><section class="my-notes">🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑🔑</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-29" class="date-read">Friday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2016/04/28/immortality-begins-at-forty/" class="title" target="_blank">Immortality Begins at Forty</a><summary class="description">I discovered something a couple of years ago: Almost all culture, old or new, is designed for consumption by people under 40. People between 40 and Ω (an…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://crapfutures.tumblr.com/post/143524228559/when-the-sun-shines" class="title" target="_blank">When the sun shines</a><summary class="description">It’s time to reveal a bit of what we’ve been doing outside the cafe. Crap Futures is keen to move beyond words (much as we like words) and put our ideas into…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/who-will-debunk-the-debunkers/" class="title" target="_blank">Who Will Debunk The Debunkers?</a><summary class="description">In 2012, network scientist and data theorist Samuel Arbesman published a disturbing thesis: What we think of as established knowledge decays over time.…</summary></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading April 17th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1460876400000:/reading/2016-04-17/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-04-17/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-04-17T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-18" class="date-read">Monday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/article/2015/10/27/joe-gibbons-artist-or-thief/2/" class="title" target="_blank">Joe Gibbons, the Bank-Robbing Filmmaker</a><summary class="description">For this former MIT instructor, art imitated life—a life of crime. Is Joe Gibbons an artist who robs banks—or a thief who makes art? By | Boston Magazine | A…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/apr/15/neoliberalism-ideology-problem-george-monbiot" class="title" target="_blank">Neoliberalism – the ideology at the root of all our problems</a><summary class="description">‘No alternative’ … Ronald Reagan and Margaret Thatcher at the White House.Photograph: Rex Features I magine if the people of the Soviet Union had never heard of…</summary><section class="my-notes">A bit ranty, but provides a good history of how neoliberal ideology transitioned from and academic ideal into a political ideology and in the process went from believing competition was the highest good to monopoly rents are rewards for efficiency. A good background on how the modern religious faith in the rightness of markets came to be. </section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-19" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.daveredfern.com/2016/why-you-should-be-using-ems/" class="title" target="_blank">Why you should be using ems - Dave Redfern</a><summary class="description">Why you should be using ems It took me quite a while to get my head around ems. When should you use them? How do they work? What are the benefits of them?…</summary><section class="my-notes">Great advice on how to use ems and maintain your sanity.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-21" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/04/eff-asks-supreme-court-overturn-dangerous-ruling-allowing-patent-owners-undermine" class="title" target="_blank">EFF Asks Supreme Court to Overturn Dangerous Ruling Allowing Patent Owners to Undermine Ownership</a><summary class="description">April 20, 2016 | By EFF Asks Supreme Court to Overturn Dangerous Ruling Allowing Patent Owners to Undermine Ownership Together with Public Knowledge and R…</summary><section class="my-notes">&quot;Intellectual property as currently constructed gotta go! Patents too!&quot; -- Omar Little</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/601299/the-curious-link-between-the-fly-by-anomaly-and-the-impossible-emdrive-thruster/" class="title" target="_blank">The Curious Link Between the Fly-By Anomaly and the “Impossible” EmDrive Thruster</a><summary class="description">About 10 years ago, a little-known aerospace engineer called Roger Shawyer made an extraordinary claim. Take a truncated cone, he said, bounce microwaves back…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://taylorpearson.me/how-to-improve-your-mindset/" class="title" target="_blank">How to Improve your Mindset</a><summary class="description">“New metaphors are capable of creating new understandings and, therefore, new realities.” – Lakoff, George; Johnson, Mark. Metaphors We Live By How many times…</summary><section class="my-notes">Changing the metaphors and metnal models you use to coneive the world is similar to changing environmental incentives, it encourages different behaviors. Thus it may be a more effective way of changing your habits.</section></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading April 10th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1460271600000:/reading/2016-04-10/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-04-10/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-04-10T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-11" class="date-read">Monday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://kneelingbus.wordpress.com/2016/04/08/unbundling-the-world/" class="title" target="_blank">Unbundling the World</a><summary class="description">Posted: April 8, 2016 | Author: | Filed under: Uncategorized | New technologies almost always seem to have less soul than whatever they replace. Music streamed…</summary><section class="my-notes">A more nuanced explanation of what happens when old forms are destroyed. More than the usual, &quot;O tempora!...&quot; humanist lament. The album was a bundle of a certain amount of music, packaging, things to make the packaging interesting (liner notes), that while dictated by the form of distribution nonetheless proivided a context for music that is absent in something like Spotify. What are the consequences of those kinds of losses?</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-12" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/04/11/gay-talese-the-voyeurs-motel" class="title" target="_blank">The Voyeur’s Motel</a><summary class="description">I know a married man and father of two who bought a twenty-one-room motel near Denver many years ago in order to become its resident voyeur. With the assistance…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Why_I_Never_Hire_Brilliant_Men" class="title" target="_blank">Why I Never Hire Brilliant Men - Wikisource, the free online library</a><summary class="description">Why I Never Hire Brilliant Men by Unknown From &quot;taoyue.com : Stacks : Why I Never Hire Brilliant Men&quot; . First appeared in the February 1924 issue of The…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-13" class="date-read">Wednesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2016/04/markov-chain-dirty-to-me.html" class="title" target="_blank">Markov Chain Dirty To Me - Charlie&#x27;s Diary</a><summary class="description">Right now, people are having sex with a computer. I don&#x27;t mean that they&#x27;re having sex with a RealDoll or similar—although I&#x27;m sure they are. I mean that there…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/13/science/alpha-centauri-breakthrough-starshot-yuri-milner-stephen-hawking.html" class="title" target="_blank">A Visionary Project Aims for Alpha Centauri, a Star 4.37 Light-Years Away</a><summary class="description">Alpha Centauri, the closest star system to Earth’s solar system. An effort led by the billionaire Yuri Milner aims to send a fleet of small probes there.…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/10/opinion/sunday/what-i-learned-from-tickling-apes.html" class="title" target="_blank">What I Learned From Tickling Apes</a><summary class="description">Enzo Pérès-Labourdette TICKLING a juvenile chimpanzee is a lot like tickling a child. The ape has the same sensitive spots: under the armpits, on the side, in…</summary><section class="my-notes">Anthropodenialism is a great idea.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://boingboing.net/2016/04/13/chip-implanted-in-paralyzed-ma.html" class="title" target="_blank">Chip implanted in paralyzed man&#x27;s brain helps him regain use of his hand</a><summary class="description">/ / 10:30 am Wed Apr 13, 2016 From the Boing Boing Shop Popular Posts Follow Boing Boing Ian Burkhart can make isolated finger movements and perform six…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://m.signalvnoise.com/to-smile-again-ae0ba9f2198c" class="title" target="_blank">To Smile Again — Signal v. Noise</a><summary class="description">Jamis Buck Mar 28 11 min read To Smile Again Recovering from the paralysis of burnout Take a moment and imagine: what if you could only smile with half of your…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-14" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/i-am-on-the-us-kill-list-this-is-what-it-feels-like-to-be-hunted-by-drones-a6980141.html" class="title" target="_blank">I am on the Kill List. This is what it feels like to be hunted</a><summary class="description">There have been 255 drone strikes on Pakistan since 2004 AP I am in the strange position of knowing that I am on the ‘Kill List’. I know this because I have…</summary><section class="my-notes">If this is true it is a heart-wrenching indictment of the drone war. </section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://status451.com/2016/01/06/splain-it-to-me/" class="title" target="_blank">Splain it to Me</a><summary class="description">Imagine you’re telling a story. Great story, unbelievable story. A series of events that if you saw them in a movie you’d roll your eyes and groan, but they…</summary><section class="my-notes">An exploration of &#x27;splaining. The author presents a view that much &#x27;splaining that goes on is a mismatch in communication styles. She defines two styles one based on social status and one based on information sharing. Much &#x27;splaining is due to one party communicating in a social status style and the other in an information sharing style. The explanation of New Yorker communication style is a very good example. This seems right but she ignores that the bird website (I love this nickname) has a large population of dishonest sea lions and trolls and they mix freely enough with the rest of the population that a lot of genuine &#x27;splaining is going on and it&#x27;s very hard to tell non-mailicious &#x27;splaining from malicious &#x27;splaining. The examples she uses are also fairly innocuous and not very emotionally charged. The stakes are fairly low when correcting someone about UNIX history, as opposed to say racism. UNIX history doesn&#x27;t really touch on a priceless value. Also, she seems blind to the status games that are played with the community of information sharers. They are different, but they are there and the assertion that information sharing status games are not zero sum is complete bullshit. Information sharers just can have different kinds of arguments without affecting status.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.alternet.org/education/why-are-k-12-school-leaders-being-trained-coercive-interrogation-techniques" class="title" target="_blank">Why Are K-12 School Leaders Being Trained in Coercive Interrogation Techniques?</a><summary class="description">One of America’s great paradoxes (or perhaps hypocrisies) is its claim to be a global beacon of freedom, even as it jails more of its citizens —by population…</summary><section class="my-notes">*facepalm*</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-15" class="date-read">Friday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.the-tls.co.uk/tls/public/article1686963.ece" class="title" target="_blank">Christopher Hitchens, from dove to hawk | TLS</a><summary class="description">Christopher Hitchens, from dove to hawk GEOFFREY WHEATCROFT Christopher Hitchens AND YET . . . 352pp. Atlantic. £20. 978 1 782 39457 0 US: Simon and Schuster.…</summary><section class="my-notes">Hitchens was a better stylist and performer than thinker. That&#x27;s a sentiment I agree with.</section></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading April 3rd, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1459666800000:/reading/2016-04-03/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-04-03/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-04-03T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-04" class="date-read">Monday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://panamapapers.sueddeutsche.de/articles/56febff0a1bb8d3c3495adf4/" class="title" target="_blank">The Panama Papers</a><summary class="description">Over a year ago, an anonymous source contacted the Süddeutsche Zeitung (SZ) and submitted encrypted internal documents from Mossack Fonseca, a Panamanian law…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://nautil.us/blog/your-roommate-is-changing-your-immune-system" class="title" target="_blank">Your Roommate Is Changing Your Immune System - Facts So Romantic - Nautilus</a><summary class="description">Our veins are swimming with immune cells of many different kinds. Some bear the memory of previous infections, in case we should encounter them again; some are…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://phys.org/news/2016-04-viking-site-north-america.html" class="title" target="_blank">Possible second Viking site discovered in North America</a><summary class="description">The &quot;Lofotr&quot; viking ship and the smaller &quot;femkeiping&quot;. Both recosntructions based on excavations from the Gokstad find. Credit: Geir Are Johansen/Wikipedia A…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://longform.org/stories/I-Wish-I-Knew-How-It-Would-Feel-To-Be-Free" class="title" target="_blank">Longform Reprints: I Wish I Knew How It Would Feel To Be Free by Joe Hagan</a><summary class="description">DON’T LET ME BE MISUNDERSTOOD The door swung open and there she was: Nina Simone, alone in her dressing room, sweat cascading down her shaved head, a wig thrown…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-05" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://medium.com/@arlogilbert/the-time-that-tony-fadell-sold-me-a-container-of-hummus-cb0941c762c1" class="title" target="_blank">The time that Tony Fadell sold me a container of hummus.</a><summary class="description">This hummus costs $2.99. Tony Fadell sold me a $299.00 empty container of hummus. On May 15th a critical Nest product will go dark. I’m shocked this isn’t…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-07" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://thingofthings.wordpress.com/2016/04/05/amateur-sociology-considered-harmful/" class="title" target="_blank">Amateur Sociology Considered Harmful</a><summary class="description">Sociology degrees are not useful for much, but one of the things a good sociology education gives you is a healthy disrespect for sociology. Bright-eyed and…</summary><section class="my-notes">A good critique of a couple of widely shared pieces of rationalist &quot;amateur sociology&quot; and a look at how frustrating and difficult sociology is in general.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://arstechnica.com/security/2016/04/nation-wide-radio-station-hack-airs-hours-of-vulgar-furry-sex-ramblings/" class="title" target="_blank">Nation-wide radio station hack airs hours of vulgar “furry sex” ramblings</a><summary class="description">TJJSvdM Some Tuesday morning listeners of KIFT, a Top 40 radio station located in Breckenridge, Colorado, were treated to a radically different programming…</summary><section class="my-notes">BWAHAHAHAHAAHAHAHHAHAHAHAA!</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-08" class="date-read">Friday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://versions.killscreen.com/what-cyberpunk-was-and-what-it-will-be/" class="title" target="_blank">What cyberpunk was and what it will be</a><summary class="description">We often forget when predicting the future that it will inevitably continue to change. Whatever we dream up, however utopian or dystopian, will be subject to…</summary></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading March 27th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1459062000000:/reading/2016-03-27/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-03-27/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-03-27T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-03-27" class="date-read">Sunday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://us1.campaign-archive1.com/?e=1eab61b26e&amp;id=9a4ed1d035&amp;u=78cbbb7f2882629a5157fa593" class="title" target="_blank">No-Brainers, Deal-Killers and Anomienomics 101</a><summary class="description">The concept of anomie , popularized by the French sociologist Émile Durkheim in 1897 (a time very like ours), should be in everybody&#x27;s mental models today. It…</summary><section class="my-notes">Decision making in the modern world is hard. In an environment of low uncertainty, like the baby boomers grew up in, there were few alternatives but it was easy to choose between good and bad moves. Now there are many options and it&#x27;s hard to tell which is which. So, instead of picking the best of few options we must eliminate the obviously bad choices and muddle through as best we can.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-03-28" class="date-read">Monday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2016/03/follow-the-money-apple-vs-the-.html" class="title" target="_blank">Follow the money: Apple vs. the FBI - Charlie&#x27;s Diary</a><summary class="description">A lot of people are watching the spectacle of Apple vs. the FBI and the Homeland Security Theatre and rubbing their eyes, wondering why Apple (in the person of…</summary><section class="my-notes">Charlie Stross argues that Apple is fighting FBI because it wants to become a bank. What else are they going to do with their massive cash stockpile? Installing a backdoor on every iphone as the FBI is requesting would undermine customers&#x27; trust in them as a bank, and rightly so. I think that is an interesting but dubious theory. The kernel of it may be correct though. I don&#x27;t know if they want to become a bank but they are a payments processor. A universal backdoor would make me much less likely to trust them with my payment information.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-03-29" class="date-read">Tuesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://github.com/reactjs/react-basic" class="title" target="_blank">reactjs/react-basic</a><summary class="description">React - Basic Theoretical Concepts This document is my attempt to formally explain my mental model of React. The intention is to describe this in terms of…</summary></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-03-30" class="date-read">Wednesday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://genius.it/thebaffler.com/blog/bottle-orange-juice-allowed-cops-kill-maim-citizens-little-consequence" class="title" target="_blank">Genius-annotated version of “How to Shoot a Suspect in the Back, Reasonably”</a><summary class="description">Beyond the racial prejudice of juries and district attorneys, a major—and frequently ignored—factor as to why county prosecutors fail to indict cops who maim…</summary><section class="my-notes">Several Supreme Court cases established standards for determining what is a reasonable use of force by a police officer. These standards are extrememly forgiving. While it seems reasonable to offer a police officer the benefit of the doubt when making what is potentially a life or death decision, the standard set is so loose that it is almost  impossible to convict a cop of excessive use of force. Worse, since those cases police have been trained how to report their use of force to make it seem as though they are in danger.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-01" class="date-read">Friday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2016/03/my_heroic_and_lazy_stand_against_ifttt/?utm_campaign=buffer&amp;utm_content=buffer8aaeb&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com" class="title" target="_blank">My Heroic and Lazy Stand Against IFTTT (Pinboard Blog)</a><summary class="description">Imagine if your sewer pipe started demanding that you make major changes in your diet. Now imagine that it got a lawyer and started asking you to sign things.…</summary><section class="my-notes">I understand the utility of having people build to you but as a provider of glue code it seems to degrade your value a bit. Also, these terms of service are absolutely nuts.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://phys.org/news/2016-03-moon-thought-major-role-earth.html" class="title" target="_blank">The moon thought to play a major role in maintaining Earth&#x27;s magnetic field</a><summary class="description">The gravitational effects associated with the presence of the Moon and Sun cause cyclical deformation of the Earth&#x27;s mantle and wobbles in its rotation axis.…</summary><section class="my-notes">The gravitational force of the moon effectively spins the Earth&#x27;s core keeping it from cooling and maintaining the Earth&#x27;s magnetic field. Cool!</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://eepurl.com/bWop_T" class="title" target="_blank">Incorrect Maps and Broken Territories</a><summary class="description">Today is April 1st, and you&#x27;re probably getting some really good practice telling pranks apart from real things in our increasingly absurd world. It&#x27;s a good…</summary><section class="my-notes">The map is not the territory. Maps are extraordinarily useful for mental compression of information but can blind you. The worst blindness is not where your map is wrong but the aspects it does not even consider and cannot accommodate. One interpretation of Fingerspitzengefuhl, finger tip feeling, is an intuitive understanding of breaks in your own and others maps. With it you can see the breaks in others maps. This jives with my own belief that you get a lot of advantage by paying attention and being observant. Many people seem to navigate by maps only. They also don&#x27;t seem to pay enough attention to actually notice when their map is wrong. Try talking to an accountant about how your business is doing. You&#x27;ll see what I mean.</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-04-02" class="date-read">Saturday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.bldgblog.com/2010/01/nakatomi-space/" class="title" target="_blank">Nakatomi Spaces</a><summary class="description">So why do I mention all this in the context of Die Hard? The majority of that film’s interest, I’d suggest, comes precisely through its depiction of architectural space: John McClane, a New York cop on his Christmas vacation, moves through a Los Angeles high-rise in basically every conceivable way but passing through its doors and hallways. McClane explores the tower—called Nakatomi Plaza—via elevator shafts and air ducts, crashing through windows from the outside-in and shooting open the locks of rooftop doorways. If there is not a corridor, he makes one; if there is not an opening, there will be soon.</summary><section class="my-notes">A great essay that I&#x27;ve read many times. It presents one of the best explanations of smooth vs. striated space (Deleuze &amp; Guattari). Think of the way a taxi driver drives, ignoring lanes, cutting through parking lots, making right turns from the left lane. Most drivers see the road as a divided group of lanes with rules and restrictions. The cabbie sees it as it is, a single piece of smooth asphalt, and treats it as such.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/florida-civil-asset-forfeiture_us_56fe9d7ce4b0a06d5805896d" class="title" target="_blank">Florida Just Made It Harder For Police To Take People&#x27;s Stuff</a><summary class="description">bjdlzx via Getty Images A new Florida law will rein in a controversial practice critics call &quot;policing for profit.&quot; Florida Gov. Rick Scott (R) on Friday signed…</summary><section class="my-notes">OMG Florida did something right!</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://phys.org/news/2016-03-indonesian-hobbits-died-sooner-thought.html" class="title" target="_blank">Indonesian &#x27;Hobbits&#x27; may have died out sooner than thought</a><summary class="description">Liang Bua, a limestone cave on the Indonesian island of Flores. The Liang Bua Team prepares for new archaeological excavations. Credit: Smithsonian Digitization…</summary><section class="my-notes">I love EVE Online. It&#x27;s so damn cyberpunk.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/20160324-in-newly-created-life-form-a-major-mystery/" class="title" target="_blank">In Newly Created Life-Form, a Major Mystery | Quanta Magazine</a><summary class="description">In Newly Created Life-Form, a Major Mystery. Peel away the layers of a house — the plastered walls, the slate roof, the hardwood floors — and you’re left with a frame, the skeletal form. Scientists have created a synthetic organism that possesses only the genes it needs to survive. But they have no idea what roughly a third of those genes do.</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://medium.com/swlh/watch-paint-dry-how-i-got-a-game-on-the-steam-store-without-anyone-from-valve-ever-looking-at-it-2e476858c753" class="title" target="_blank">Watch Paint Dry: How I got a game on the Steam Store without anyone from Valve ever looking at it. — The Startup</a><summary class="description">Watch Paint Dry: How I got a game on the Steam Store without anyone from Valve ever looking at it. Was getting caught part of your plan? Of course! If you were…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://phys.org/news/2016-03-indonesian-hobbits-died-sooner-thought.html" class="title" target="_blank">Indonesian &#x27;Hobbits&#x27; may have died out sooner than thought</a><summary class="description">Liang Bua, a limestone cave on the Indonesian island of Flores. The Liang Bua Team prepares for new archaeological excavations. Credit: Smithsonian Digitization…</summary><section class="my-notes">Humans may have burned the Shire when they arrived in Indonesia.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2016/03/31/human-complete-problems/" class="title" target="_blank">Human-Complete Problems</a><summary class="description">Occasionally, I manage to be clever when I am not even trying to be clever, which isn’t often. In a recent conversation about the new class of doomsday…</summary><section class="my-notes">Human complete problems are the hard problems for humans like finding meaning, earning a living, life the universe and everything. Human complete problems are infinite games. Some of them contain sets of finite games. Fulfilling Life = &lt;Make a living, Do interesting work, Raise happy children, Learn&gt; ... or something like that. This provides an interesting way to classify AI, potentially more interesting than the Turing test. An AI is a general purpose AI (AGI) if it can play human complete infinite games. Can AlphaGo make a living as AlphaGo? Can the Google car get fired from being a self-driving car and retrain itself as a piece of mining equipment, quit Google and start a job as a party bus. There&#x27;s a lot more packed into this post than that but it&#x27;s a start.</section></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/03/american-cities-are-booming-for-rich-young-college-grads-without-kids/475995/" class="title" target="_blank">American Cities Are Booming* (*For Rich Young College Grads Without Kids)</a><summary class="description">Americans aren’t moving back to the cities. Just 20- and 30-somethings. But actually, not all 20- and 30-somethings are moving back to the cities.…</summary></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading March 20th, 2016]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1458457200000:/reading/2016-03-20/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//reading/2016-03-20/">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-03-20T07:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="notes-by-day"><section><h3><time datetime="2016-03-24" class="date-read">Thursday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/601107/data-mining-reveals-the-four-urban-conditions-that-create-vibrant-city-life/" class="title" target="_blank">Data Mining Reveals the Four Urban Conditions That Create Vibrant City Life</a><summary class="description">Back in 1961, the gradual decline of many city centers in the U.S. began to puzzle urban planners and activists alike. One of them, the urban sociologist Jane…</summary><section class="my-notes">Jane Jacobs was right! The key factors in creating a vibrant city are about maximizing serendipitous interactions and physical connectivity: dense intersections, mixed use areas, meeting places (aka third places)...</section></article></li></ol></section><section><h3><time datetime="2016-03-25" class="date-read">Friday</time></h3><ol class="reading-notes-list"><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://medium.com/@robbyrussell/d-oh-my-zsh-af99ca54212c" class="title" target="_blank">d’Oh My Zsh</a><summary class="description">How I unexpectedly built a monster of an open source project This wouldn’t my first foray into open source software; nor my last. It was the summer of 2009. I…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://splitsider.com/2011/03/your-favorite-comedy-exists-because-of-the-larry-sanders-show/" class="title" target="_blank">Your Favorite Comedy Exists Because of ‘The Larry Sanders Show’</a><summary class="description">This year the IFC channel started showing reruns of The Larry Sanders Show , which will hopefully introduce one of the best, most influential sitcoms of all…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2016/03/24/the-holy-grail-of-self-improvement/" class="title" target="_blank">The Holy Grail of Self-Improvement</a><summary class="description">The holy grail of self-improvement in modern times is a framework for individual experimentation and learning that can be used by the average person. The key…</summary></article></li><li><article class="reading-note"><a href="https://medium.com/@nm_johnson/npm-package-hijacking-from-the-hijackers-perspective-af0c48ab9922" class="title" target="_blank">NPM Package Hijacking: From the Hijackers Perspective</a><summary class="description">In light of recent events in the javascript community, I would like to share the story of how I came into control of more than 200 heavily depended on modules,…</summary></article></li></ol></section></div>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attribution Errors]]></title>
        <id>tag:brittcrawford.com,1397520000000:/blog/2015-04-15/</id>
        <link href="http://brittcrawford.com//blog/2015-04-15/">
        </link>
        <updated>2014-04-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is an argument that I frequently have with my wife Dara about our children. We’ll be talking a behavior that we find annoying or want to try and control, like whining, and I will say, “Well it’s a strategy that he’s learned to get a treat.” Dara will counter, “He’s 5 years old. Five year olds don’t think like that. They’re not manipulative like that.” <em>This echoes an argument that we often have with my mother and other people of her generation that who seem to think of babies and children as manipulative little schemers.</em> I think there’s some truth to this but I don’t think they are intentionally manipulative. Intention is the difference. No matter how many times we have this conversation I end up explaining, “I don’t mean that he’s making a plan to deceive you into getting a cookie. I mean that he’s learned by stimulus and response that if he does this he’ll get a cookie. The process is unconscious.”</p>
<p>I think there are a great many people, my wife included, who model people as having only conscious thought processes. I think intellectually they understand the idea of the unconscious but their everyday model of people only includes conscious cognition. It seems to extend to perceptions of systems as well. There are people who see a racist system (on with racist outcomes) and conclude that it must have been planned to institute oppression. Sometimes that’s true, FHA red-lining being a good example, but sometimes it’s not.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>